# **DANIEL**HAMPTON

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | AUSTIN, TX

Over the past eight years I have made a career of solving problems with technology. Though my primary job responsibilities have mostly been web development, I have always found myself working with various systems and tools and finding creative ways to add value and improve processes. I am currently looking for a job that will present new challenges and provide the opportunity to attempt things that haven't been done before.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER, HOMEPAY BY CARE.COM

JANUARY 2017 TO CURRENT

- C#/Dotnet Core, Go, Docker, Github, Couchbase, Kafka, Bash
- WRITING AND CONTAINERIZING MICROSERVICES
- Helped develop a custom container orchestration system with Consul/Vault/Prometheus/Grafana/Traefik
- PROJECT PLANNING, GATHERING REQUIREMENTS, SETTING TEAM MILESTONES, DEVELOPING TEAM PROCESSES.

## SHAREPOINT DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD, PHILLIPS 66

JUNE 2013 TO DECEMBER 2016

- C#, MVC, ENTITY FRAMEWORK, WEBAPI, JAVASCRIPT, REACT/REDUX, NINJECT/MOQ/NUNIT, POWERSHELL, SQL, REST, JSON, TFS VC
- TECHNICAL LEAD ON SEVERAL LARGE PROJECTS.
- TECH MENTOR FOR NEW EMPLOYEES.
- SOLUTION DESIGN FOR THE SP2013 PLATFORM.
- AGILE PROJECT PLANNING, GATHERING REQUIREMENTS, PRIORITIZING TASKS,
   COORDINATING TESTING, DELEGATING WORK, DEVELOPING TEAM PROCESSES.

## SAP Developer, Phillips 66/Conocophillips

NOVEMBER 2010 TO JUNE 2013

- ABAP, WebDynpro, Abap Objects, Winshuttle Development
- PRIMARY RESPONSIBILITIES INCLUDED ABAP DEVELOPMENT AND WINSHUTTLE ADMINISTRATION.
- Participated in technical efforts to support company split in 2012.
- PRIMARY SUPPORT AND TEAM LEAD FOR WINSHUTTLE DEVELOPMENT,
  SUPPORT, DOCUMENTATION, LICENSE MANAGEMENT, PERMISSIONS, UPGRADES,
  TRAINING, AND WORKING WITH VENDOR.

#### REFINING OPERATIONS ANALYST (DEVELOPER), CONOCOPHILLIPS

AUG 2008 TO NOVEMBER 2010

- C#, JAVASCRIPT, SQL, PHP, TFS VC
- WORKED ON AN AGILE PROJECT TEAM THAT DEVELOPED AND IMPLEMENTED A CUSTOM WEB APPLICATION BUILT ON TOP OF SHAREPOINT 2007 THAT COMBINED DATA FROM VARIOUS REFINERY MONITORING SYSTEMS.
- ENHANCED APPLICATION FUNCTIONALITY AND WROTE IN FUNCTIONALITY TO ALLOW MANY ONE-OFF APPLICATIONS TO BE RETIRED.
- END USER SUPPORT AND TRAINING.

#### **SKILLS**

CODING

**SOLUTION DESIGN** 

**PROBLEM SOLVING** 

**COMMUNICATION** 

**DOCUMENTATION** 

Learning

MENTORING

**PROCESS CREATION** 

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

**C#/DOTNET CORE** 

**JAVASCRIPT** 

Go

DOCKER

GIT / GITHUB

XUNIT, MOQ, GINKGO

COUCHBASE

Kafka

MVC

REST

# **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN

COMPUTER SCIENCE

MINOR IN MATHEMATICS

University of Tulsa

Tulsa, Oklahoma Graduated May 2008

GPA: 3.8





